Hohstadt Family papers, 1893-1944
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Hohstadt Family papers, 1893-1944
MS 150
Hohstadt family
Cattle ranchers and mine operators from Douglas, Arizona; ventures in Arizona, New Mexico, and Sonora, Mexico. Companies include Corona Mining Company, Hohstadt Group, and Progress Mining Company. Mexican ranches include La Pera, Batana, Guepare, and Turicachi
1.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Cattle ranchers and mine operators from Douglas, Arizona; ventures in Arizona, New Mexico, and Sonora, Mexico. Companies include Corona Mining Company, Hohstadt Group, and Progress Mining Company. Mexican ranches include La Pera, Batana, Guepare, and Turicachi.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series.
Series I: Mexican Properties (Arizpe District, Sonora), 1893-1940
Series II: Progress Mining Company and Miscellaneous Material, 1916-1944
Series III: John F. Hohstadt Financial Records, 1900-1929
Scope and Content Note
Collection of correspondence and legal papers, including original deeds. Financial records relate chiefly to the ranching and mining activities of John F. Hohstadt, and his brother, Lewis A. Hohstadt. One file contains papers of Robert A. Hohstadt, Lewis A.'s son. Other materials are claims through the U.S. government against the Mexican government by Lewis A. Hohstadt, for losses caused by the Mexican Revolution and agrarian land reforms. Obituaries for both brothers are present.
Some material is in Spanish.
Hohstadt, Lewis Alman, 1864-1944 -- Archives; Hohstadt, John F., 1861-1929 -- Archives; Hohstadt, Robert A; Hohstadt family -- Archives; Hohstadt Group -- Records and correspondence; Corona Mining Company -- Records and correspondence; Progress Mining Co. -- Records and correspondence; Mining corporations -- Mexico -- Sonora (State) -- Records and correspondence; Ranches -- Mexico -- Sonora (State) -- Records and correspondence; Mining corporations -- New Mexico -- Records and correspondence; Ranches -- Arizona -- Records and correspondence; Land reform -- Mexico -- Sonora (State) -- Sources; Correspondence; Deeds; Claims
Container List
- Series I: Mexican Properties (Arizpe District, Sonora), 1893-1940
  - Mines: Corona Mining Company (includes plans and deeds). 1893-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mines: Hohstadt Group (includes surveys, assay reports, and bills for supplies). 1906-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ranches (includes titles, livestock records, bills for supplies, land rental - relating to La Pera, Batana, Guepare and Turicachi Ranches). 1899-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ranches: Legal Matters (includes correspondence and legal papers relating to succession of estate of John F. Hohstadt, claims against the government for expropriation, and sale of land). 1931-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ranches: Legal Matters (includes claims through the U. S. government against the Mexican government by Lewis A. Hohstadt regarding losses due to the Mexican Revolution and agrarian reforms). 1924-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mines and Ranches: Taxes and valuations. 1915-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mines and Ranches: Account books. 1915, 1922, 1924, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Progress Mining Company and Miscellaneous Material, 1916-1944
  - Progress Mining Company: Mine claims, articles of incorporation. 1916 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Progress Mining Company: Annual reports, sale of stock, work reports. 1917-1922 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Progress Mining Company: Dissolution, New Mexico property taxes. 1923-1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lewis A. Hohstadt Financial Records (includes property taxes, bank statements and checks). 1917-1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - John F. Hohstadt Estate (see also Box 1, Folder 4). 1929 (Death) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John F. Hohstadt: Correspondence (includes correspondence with E. B. Perrin of Williams, Arizona concerning loans and promissory notes, J. F. B. Erdletz of New York concerning Mexican mine situation and proposal for Discovery Mining and Development, Co.). 1912-1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - John and Lewis Hohstadt: Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Robert A. Hohstadt: Miscellaneous (includes bank records, personal letter of Frank Hohstadt). 1929-1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series III: John F. Hohstadt Financial Records, 1900-1929
  - Financial Records: Bank statements from Bank of Bisbee and First National Bank of Douglas. 1901-1929 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Financial Records: Checks (includes some stubs, deposit slips and promissory notes). 1900-1929 (Box 3, Folder 5-9)
- Series I: Mexican Properties (Arizpe District, Sonora) - Continued, 1893-1940
  - Mexican Mine Deeds (oversize). 1898-1900 (Box 4)